Guide to the New York City Tavern License Collection 1783-1797, 1862 MS 443.28
New-York Historical Society
New-York Historical Society collection of New York City tavern licenses
1783-1797, 1862
New-York Historical Society
MS 443.28
0.42 Linear Feet in one document box
The collection includes about 400 tavern licenses, plus many related excise tax receipts, from New York City dating from the 1780s and 1790s. One outlying exception is an 1862 license for a tavern in Morrisania, Westchester County. The collection as a whole was compiled over time by New-York Historical Society from various donations, especially those of former N-YHS President Samuel V. Hoffman.
Arrangement Note
There is no particular order to the overall collection, but generally the earlier licenses (circa 1784) are in the first folders and the later licenses (1790s) are in the later folders. A broader mix of dates are found in the fourth folder, including the 1862 outlier. Within some folders, the documents are arranged by license number.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers. Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. (Researchers may not accrue unused copy amounts from previous days.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
The collection as a whole was compiled over time by New-York Historical Society from various donations and a purchase. All but ten of the licenses were donated to N-YHS by a former N-YHS President Samuel V. Hoffman, on four different dates: 3 January 1910, 26 November 1923, 21 September 1926, and 7 October 1926. One license was likely received as part of a bequest of manuscripts from Hoffman on 21 April 1943 (see folder 3). Other donated licenses were: one by Thomas P. Teale on 5 October 1847 (see folder 5); three by Robert F. Seybolt on 27 September 1932 and 20 September 1939 (see folder 4); one by E.B. Child on 23 March 1933 (see folder 4); and one by C. Otto von Kienbusch on 6 January 1958 (see folder 4). Four licenses with affidavits were purchased on 15 January 1918 (see folder 3).
Scope and Contents Note
The collection includes about 400 tavern licenses, plus many related excise tax receipts, from New York City dating from the 1780s and 1790s. There is one outlying exception to this: an 1862 license for a tavern in Morrisania, Westchester County. The licenses are signed by the New York City mayors of the time, James Duane and Richard Varick, and the excise receipts are signed by Commissioner of Excise and Alderman Abraham P. Lott. The licenses were granted to a variety of individuals and pertain to several wards of the city. The licenses of the 1790s refer to the licensee's occupation (often grocer or innkeeper, but others appear as well) or to whether a woman licensee is a widow (licenses of the 1780s have "innkeeper" preprinted on the form). The container list below includes an item level description of all the documents in the collection.
Taverns (Inns) -- Taxation; Licenses; New York (N.Y.); Duane, James; Varick, Richard
- 12. South Ward. John McKinsey (Innholder); Michael Dondry; William Chiveres, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  With excise receipt dated 1784 February 1
- 13. South Ward. John Simmons (Innholder); Robert Benson; William Simmons, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 14. South Ward. Elias Stilwell (Innholder); James McCullen; Zacharias Sickles, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 15. North Ward. Christopher Bloom (Innholder); Robert Thomas; Andrew Onger, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 16. Montgomery Ward. Asher Cook (Innholder); Robert Manly; Thomas Ash, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 February 2
- 17. North Ward. John Stilwell (Innholder); George Garland; Samuel Lillick, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 18. East Ward. Robert Magee (Innholder); James Wilkes; Malachi Hanley, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 February 1. Robert Magee is from Dock Ward
- 19. West Ward (Warren Street). John Sanford (Innholder); John Van North; John Sabine, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 20. Dock Ward. John Wyckhoff (Innholder); Henry Wyckhoff; John W. Vradenburgh, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 21. South Ward. Christopher Beakley (Innholder); John Montanie; Abraham Lazilin, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 22. Montgomery Ward. Godfrey Coon (Innholder); John Montanie; Abraham Lazilin, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 23. North Ward. Henry Merchant (Innholder); John Stilwell; Myndert Van Evesen, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 24. South Ward (Whitehall). William Colberson (Innholder); William James; Arthur Dunn, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 25. South Ward. Daniel Jones (Innholder); William Corwin; Daniel Ross, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 26. South Ward. William Corwin (Innholder); Daniel Jones; Daniel Ross, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 27. South Ward. Daniel Ross (Innholder); William Corwin; Daniel Jones, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 28. North Ward. Andrew Bostwick (Innholder); Samuel LaRue; William Patterson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 29. West Ward. Duncan Jameson (Innholder); Francis Read; James Richardson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 30. Dock Ward. Francis Read (Innholder); James Richardson; Duncan Jameson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 31. East Ward. William Peal (Innholder); Daniel Jones; Robert McCae, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 32. East Ward. Daniel Green (Innholder); Thomas White; Thomas Warner, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 33. Montgomery Ward. Thomas White (Innholder); Daniel Green; Thomas Warner, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 34. East Ward. Thomas Warner (Innholder); Daniel Green; Thomas White, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 35. West Ward. John Van Antwerp (Innholder); Jacobus Van Antwerp; Nicholas Van Antwerp, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 March 29
- 36. Dock Ward (Cougars Wharf). Peter McMarton (Innholder); James Stewart; Michael McKinnon, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 March 25
- 37. South Ward (Moore Street). Mary Dickson (Innholder); Jacob Burness (?); James Richardson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 March 18
- 38. South Ward. Ann Boyd (Innholder); Henry Sheaf; Richard Spencer, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 March 30
- 39. Dock Ward. John Van North (Innholder); Charles Derby; John Johnson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 40. North Ward. Michail Farmer (Innholder); Lewis Herrington; Ebenezer Carson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 41. South Ward. William Masters (Innholder); Ephriam Ross; Daniel Ross, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 42. South Ward. Ephraim Ross (Innholder); Daniel Ross; William Masters, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 43. Out Ward. George Commons (Innholder); Vardin Elsworth; Theophilus Beekman, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 March 31
- 44. South Ward. William H. Mason (Innholder); William Mason; George Ford, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 45. South Ward (N4). George Ford (Innholder); William Mason; William H. Mason, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 46. Montgomery Ward. Mary Carson (Innholder); Ezekiel Robins; Augustus Sidell, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 47. Out Ward. Elijah Wedge (Innholder); Isaac Peffer; Lewis Peffer, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 48. Dock Ward. Samuel Milligan (Innholder); Robert Nesbitt; Ephraim Ross, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 49. South Ward. Elizabeth Carswell (Innholder); James Carter; Joseph Keys, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 1
- 50. South Ward. James Lent (Innholder); William Dean; John Lawrence, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 51. West Ward. Aron Ackerman (Innholder); Abraham Marlin; John Delancey, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 March 26
- 52. South Ward. Andrew Erwin (Innholder); Izrael Philips; Patrick Hagens, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 5
- 53. Out Ward. Archibald McDonald (Innholder); John Graham Timman; William Williams, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents Note
  McDonald lived in North Ward according to Excise Receipt. With excise receipt dated 1784 April 6
- 54. North Ward. Isaac Montanyea (Innholder); Thomas Lefoy Thomas White, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 6
- 55. Dock Ward (Water Street). Caleb Carr (Innholder); William Little; Samuel Shiter, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 2
- 64. East Ward. Eunice Welsh (Innholder); John Lovely; William Peak, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 23
- 65. West Ward. John Tompkins (Innholder); Barnadus Swantwort; George Garland, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 66. Montgomery Ward. Margaret Ann Lent (Innholder); Elizabeth Smith; John Smyers, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 26
- 67. Montgomery Ward. Abraham Anderson (Innholder); George Garland; Elias Stillwell, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  ggg
- 68. East Ward. Ann Higgins (Innholder); Cornelius Room; Richard Norris, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 27
- 69. Montgomery Ward. John Lawrence (Innholder); Rissia Sheats; Cornelius Room, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 70. North Ward. James Gilland (Innholder); Cornelius Room; Ann Higgins, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 71. Out Ward. John Gatsey (Innholder); George Stanley; John Lovely, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 72. West Ward. Mary Storm (Innholder); Andrew Looie; William Needham, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 May 13. Mary Storm from Out Ward
- 73. Montgomery Ward. John Lovely (Innholder); James O'Flagherty; William Roach, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 May 13
- 74. Dock Ward. William Evert (Innholder); James Tyler; Jotham Pool, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 May 8
- 75. Out Ward. Frederick Shober (Innholder); Robert Hodge; Thomas Nixen, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 May 11
- 76. West Ward. Aaron Gibson (Innholder); John McQuain; John Disney, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 77. Dock Ward. Samuel Carmen (Innholder); James Tyler; Jonathan Pool, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 April 28
- 78. Montgomery Ward. William Collins (Innholder); John Morgan; James O'Flagherty, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 79. North Ward. William Clarke (Innholder); Lawrence Brasher; (unreadable) Degrovo, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 80. Dock Ward. Lewis Herrington (Innholder); Michael Fernos; Ebenezer Caston, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 81. Out Ward. Michael Brillois (Innholder); Bosyn Kaens (?); Henry Willen, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 May 12
- 82. West Ward. Henrick Bogart (Innholder); Phillip Fea; Elbert Bogart, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 83. Out Ward. Timothy Clawson (Innholder); Daniel Tier; Timothy McCarly, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 May 26
- 84. Dock Ward. Moses Morse (Innholder); James Weir; Joseph Cutler, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 May 24
- 85. West Ward. James Sharp (Innholder); James Riker; William Williams, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 86. West Ward. Harculas Windover (Innholder); Harculas Windover, Jr.; John Tompkins, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 87. Out Ward. Godfree Spannegal (Innholder); William Leonard; Matthias Balom, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 89. South Ward. Thomas Mears (Innholder); William James; Charles Maals, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 90. Montgomery Ward. Palatiah Hawes (Innholder); John Buchannan; John Kile, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 91. West Ward. Robert Bonsall (Innholder); Joseph Beck; John Anderson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 92. Dock Ward. John Robinson (Innholder); Alexander Quincy; Ferdinand Little, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 93. North Ward. Asher Pick (Innholder); Marimus Willet; John Delemeter, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 94. West Ward. Cornelius L. Bogart (Innholder); William Day; James Bogart, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 3
- 95. Out Ward. James Bosworth (Innholder); John (unreadable); Joshua Tucker, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 1
- 96. Montgomery Ward. Francis Cooley (Innholder); John Sise; Niel McKinnon, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 2. Cooley is from North Ward
- 97. East Ward. Deborah Monrow (Innholder); Robert Magee; Michael Kelly, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 5
- 98. East Ward. Lucretia McKinsay (Innholder); William Rutherford; Hugh Tarbet, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 8
- 99. Dock Ward. John Gillchand (Innholder); Daniel Shaw; Abraham Hopper, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- 100. East Ward. Isaac Norton (Innholder); William Smith; Ebenezer Miller, Jr., 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 10
- 101. North Ward. John Leitch (Innholder); Adolph DeGrove, Jr.; Hattie and William DeGrove (Shoemaker), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 15
- 102. West Ward. John Van Allen (Innholder); William Egles; John Hogg, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 February 02
- 103. Out Ward. Stephen Davenport (Innholder); Henry Shule (Grocer); Abraham Bancher (Cordswainer), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 104. West Ward. Margaret McNail (Innholder); James Erwin; John Ryan, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 105. Out Ward. Emanuel Jockey (Innholder); John DeGrove; Guiliam Lusner, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 106. South Ward. William Black (Innholder); William Young; Hugh Glen, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 January 3
- 107. Out Ward. Geradus Hardenbroock (Innholder); William Snyder; Daniel Shafer, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 29
- 108. Montgomery Ward. John Harrison (Innholder); Robert Johnson; Bartholomew Ryan, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 109. Montgomery Ward. John Van Varick (Innholder); Rissia Shaats; William Shaats, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 30
- 110. North Ward. Peter Van Kleeck (Innholder); Andrew Johnson; Elias Kepp, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 July 1
- 111. Montgomery Ward. David Ficks (Innholder); Peter Hulick; Richard Penny, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 112. Montgomery Ward. Isaac Delamater, Jr. (Innholder); William Allen; John Delamater, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 113. South Ward. David McFee (Innholder); Daniel Kelsey; James Hay, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 114. Montgomery Ward. John Moore (Innholder); James Lemasny; William Byan, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 July 6
- 115. East Ward. Elizabeth Hoagland (Innholder); John Moore; Thomas Warner, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 116. Montgomery Ward. John Mackintash (Innholder); Thomas Arden; Neil McKinnon, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 117. Montgomery Ward. Thomas Dunn (Innholder); Robert Smith; Robert Gailen, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 June 7
- 125. West Ward. James Barret (Innholder); John Anderson; Daniel (unreadable), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 July 7
- 126. Out Ward. Jane Williams (Innholder); Henry Ackerman; Edward Simmons, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 July 28
- 127. North Ward. John Parks (Innholder); Christopher Eninger; Abraham Ingham, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 July 27
- 128. North Ward. Lewis Pepper (Innholder); Charles Meal; John Camp, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 129. South Ward. John Riley (Innholder); William Peel; Edward Rogers, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 130. Out Ward (Harlam). Lawrence Myers (Innholder); William Muir; Valentine Vaughn (?), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 133. North Ward. Daniel Shaver (Innholder); Gerarden (unreadable); (unreadable) Garrett, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 136. East Ward. Dennis Leary (Innholder); William GoForth; Benjamin Van Winck, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 September 9
- 137. Montgomery Ward. Prudent LaJennisson (Innholder); Thomas Warren; Joseph Burgill, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 September 1
- 139. Out Ward. William Cowan and William Hunter (Innholders); James Mars, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 September 3
- 140. East Ward. John Walsh (Innholder); Matthew Van (unreadable); Phillip Lott, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 September 6
- 141. West Ward. William Yeats (Innholder); Samuel Clarke; Thomas Ferguson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 August 17
- 142. South Ward. Elizabeth DeLavine (Innholder); James Brunton; John Dickson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  With excise receipt dated 1784 July 25
- 143. South Ward. Mary Arkin (Innholder); Dunkin Zimmerson; William Mason, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 144. Ward ?. Hugh Doyle (Innholder); George Ford; Francis Reed, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Excise Tax Receipts Only for Isaac Vervalen (West Ward); Daniel Burger (North Ward - Franck Ford Street); Benjamin Baldwin (Dock Ward - 19 Water Street); James Quackenbush (North Ward - Maiden Lane); Isaac Austin (South Ward - 18 Moore's Street); Daniel Kilsey (South Ward), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- 164. East Ward. William Lawler (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  With excise receipt dated 1785 March 1.
- 165. Ward ?. John Parks (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  With excise receipt dated 1785 March 1
- 166. Ward ?. Nicholas Bogart (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 168. South Ward (Dock Street). Abraham Bond (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 169. West Ward (No. 4 Cortlandt Street). Thomas Murphy (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 170. Montgomery Ward (New Slip). Ebenezer Hudson (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 171. South Ward (No. 67). Richardson Ryan (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 172. Out Ward (No. 40). Elias Anderson (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 173. South Ward (Broad Street). John Wilkes (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 174. Montgomery Ward (131 Water Street). George Rawson (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 175. Montgomery Ward. Joseph Beck (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 176. East Ward. (No. 6 Depester Street). Matthew Casey (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 177. Ward ?. Abraham Hobby (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 179. North Ward (No. 16 Barrack Street). George Beekman (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 180. Montgomery Ward (Catham Street). Daniel Ross (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 181. Dock Ward (No. 31 Dock Street). Jacob Weser (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 182. West Ward (No. 385 Capel Street). Catharine Clarck (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 183. Out Ward. John Barny (innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 184. Montgomery Ward (No. 17 Fair Street). John Hicks (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 185. West Ward (143 Nassau Street). Abraham Van Emburgh (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 186. East Ward (M. Land). James Hearn (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 187. South Ward (71 Broad Street). John Anderson (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 188. North Ward (Ann Street). Peregrine Sandford (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 189. West Ward (54 Warrents Street). John Sandford (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 190. Dock Ward (Princes Street). Robert Hargrave (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 191. East Ward (No. 12). Samuel Carman (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 192. North Ward (No. 71). Ephraim Ross (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 193. West Ward (12 Great George Street). Samuel Walters (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 194. West Ward (10 Reed Street). Henry Lorum (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 195. East Ward (10 King Street). Francis King (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 196. South Ward (No. 9, near Exchange).James Lent (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 337. Out Ward (No. 36). John Goddard (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Excise Receipt only for Moses Gale, 1786 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 170. Out Ward. John Hoffman (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- License ?. Ward ?. William Dyckman (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1785 November 16
- License ?. Ward ?. Christopher Hullman (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1785 November 3
- License ?. Ward ?. William A. Coat (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1785 December 21
- License ?. Ward ?. Joseph Adam Fleming (Innholder), 1785 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1785 December 14
- License ?. Ward ?. James Gibbons (Innholder), 1786 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1786 September 16
- License ?. Ward ?. John Leggett (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1789 March 19
- License ?. Ward ?. John Michael Kemp (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- License ?. Ward ?. John Kaven (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- License ?. Ward ?. Francis Giffin (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- License ?. Ward ?. John M. Ray (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1789 March 16
- License ?. Ward ?. James Richardson (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1789 March 7
- License ?. Ward ?. James Fleming (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- License ?. Ward ?. William Henry (Innholder), 1789 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1789 March 10
- 10. North Ward. George Garland (Innholder); George Garland, Jr.; John Stilwell, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 March 11
- 9. North Ward. George Garland, Jr. (Innholder); George Garland; Samuel Lillick, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 8. Montgomery Ward. Samuel Lillick (Innholder); George Garland; John Stilwell, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 6. North Ward. James Quackenbush (Innholder); David Van Der Beck; Daniel Van Norm, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 March 8. There is a corresponding excise receipt in folder 2.
- 5. Dock Ward. Mary Clemson (Innholder); Abraham Van Gelden; Joseph Pattson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 March 6
- 3. South Ward. Isaac Austin (Innholder); Rimin Skates; Bartholomew Skates, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 March 6. There is a corresponding excise receipt in folder 2.
- 63. Montgomery Ward. Oliver Glean (Innholder); George Taylor; Robert Benson, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 April 22
- 62. Out Ward. Sarah Shin (Innholder); Elias Anderson; Joseph Varian, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 61. Out Ward. Elias Anderson (Innholder); Joseph Varian; Sarah Shin, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 60. Montgomery Ward. Ann Arcson (Innholder); John Buchanan; Benjamin Egberts, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 April 21
- 59. Montgomery Ward. John Buchanan (Innholder); Benjamin Egberts; John Kerso, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 58. West Ward. Isaac Vervelen (Innholder); George Nigday; Isaac Blacwell, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 April 20. There is a corresponding excise receipt in folder 2.
- 57. South Ward. Daniel Kilsey (Innholder); John Clark; Elijah Price, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- 56. South Ward. Ezekiel Crane; Silvanus Sechy; Daniel Dunsevence (?), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 April 8
- 4. North Ward. Daniel Burger (Innholder); John Strickland; Richard Varian, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 March 10. There is a corresponding excise receipt in folder 2.
- 7. Dock Ward. Benjamin Baldwin (Innholder); Joseph Clemens; James Woodnik (?), 1784 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1784 March 8. There is a correspondinig excise receipt in folder 2.
- License ?. First Ward. Joseph Williams (Innholder, grocer), 1796 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1796 March 5
- 272. Dock Ward. Joseph Williams (Innholder, grocer), 1791 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1791 March 7
- 287. West Ward. Wiliam Williams (Innholder, grocer), 1791 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1791 March 10
- 126. Out Ward. John Corlant (Innholder, grocer), 1791 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1791 March 2
- Signed Tavern License, Not Assigned, 18-- (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Signed by Flores Baneker, Supervisor; Daniel Wagar and Daniel Simmons (Justices of the Peace) -- all three Commissioners of Excise
- 424. Seventh Ward. Zeno Weeks (Innholder, grocer), 1797 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1797 March 7
- License. Morrisania, Westchester County, NY. Frederick Zelling Tavern License, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Franklin Avenue, Morrisania Town, Westchester, NY
- 79. Dock Ward. Bernard Cleodon (Innholder), 1790 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dated 1790 March 4
- 455. Sixth Ward. Joseph Watkins (Innholder, grocer), 1797 (Box 1, Folder 4)